早上好
Morning!
中杯脱脂拿铁
Grande skim latte,
双压合成无糖香草  再加一块杏仁馅饼
Two pumps sugar-free vanilla and a bear claw.
-你怎么知道  -我是个小说家
- How did you know-- - I'm a novelist.
我的工作就是留意生活
It's my job to notice things.
星期天一清早
It's Sunday morning.
应该是你花天酒地完后回家的时候吧
Shouldn't you be slinking home from a scandalous liaison?
如果真是这样  你会吃醋吗
Would you be jealous if I were?
做梦去吧
In your dreams.
其实  在我的梦里你从来不吃醋
Actually, in my dreams you're never jealous.
在我的梦里  你会一起来...
In my dreams, you just joined in
蒙哥马利打电话说他马上过来
Well, Montgomery called and said, "come down right away,"
所以这个案子肯定不一般
So it must be gruesome.
每次我们去案发现场的时候
Try not to get so giddy
别显得那么开心好吗
Every time we go to a crime scene, okay?
不过死个人  不必这么气急败坏吧
Just 'cause somebody's dead doesn't mean you have to be grumpy.
想看看什么叫做气急败坏吗
Oh, do you want to see grumpy?
看看你那本新书的封面
How about the cover art for your new novel?
你是指《妮基·希特》的封面吗
"Nikki heat" cover art?
封面不是只能在...
That's only available to..
上帝啊  你到我的网页上注册了吧
Oh, my god. You subscribe to my web site?
等等  你是"我为卡塞尔狂1212"吗
Wait a minute. Are you castlefreak1-2-1-2?
"卡塞尔情人45"
Castlelover45?
你知不知道很多人
You do realize that
被匿名的疯狂粉丝吓跑的
Most people would be creeped out by crazy, anonymous fans?
你这样的粉丝
Like you?
我完全是出于职业好奇心
It was strictly professional curiosity.
觉得你这个新生形象如何
So what did you think of your alter ego Nikki?
-很甜美吧  -那叫甜美
- Pretty sweet, right? - "Sweet"?
那是一丝不挂
She's naked!
并非一丝不挂  构图上看她还挂着一把枪
She's not naked. She's holding a gun...strategically.
要知道...
You know...
令我感到好受一些的是
I take comfort in the fact
这本书一旦问世
That if they're already publishing the cover art,
你连书带人就跟我们没什么瓜葛了
Then your book and our little partnership is almost done.
咖啡不能拿进去  先生
No coffee in here, sir.
长官  出什么事了
Sir, what's going on?
一个两岁的女孩  安吉拉·坎德拉失踪了
2-Year-Old girl, Angela Candela,
大概早上八点她父母报的案
Reported missing by her parents about 8:00 this morning.
尸体在哪里发现的
Where'd they find the body?
还没找到  她被绑架了
They haven't found her. She was abducted.
当时她爸爸在隔壁房间画画
Father was in the other room painting.
在她家里遭到绑架
Kidnapped from her home?
我不明白  长官  如果不是谋杀
I don't understand, sir. If this isn't a murder,
要我来干嘛
Why am I here?
联邦调查局要你来的
The feds requested you to be on the task force.
联邦调查局
Feds?
联调局对儿童绑架案有管理权限
FBI has jurisdiction over child abduction cases.
那要我来干嘛
Then why call me?
因为我想气气联调局这帮家伙
'Cause I like pissing off the FBI,
还有  你从不按常理出牌
And because you think outside the box.
这是联调局的人员做不到的
That's something the febs rarely do.
长官  谁负责这案子
Sir, who's the special agent in charge?
-贝克特  这不重要  -长官  是谁
- Beckett, it doesn't matter-- - Sir, who?
索伦森
Sorenson.
谁是索伦森
Who's Sorenson?
我还以为他在
I thought that he was in--
波士顿  调离了  他回来了
In boston. Not anymore. He's here.
谁是索伦森
Who's Sorenson?
不会有什么问题吧  警探
This isn't gonna be a problem, is it, detective?
我们都是专业人士  是吧
I mean, we're all professionals here, right?
其实  我不专业  谁是索伦森
Actually, I'm not. Who's Sorenson?
没问题  长官
No, sir. Not a problem.
不管怎样
For what it's worth,
失踪的女童年或受惊吓的父母
That missing little girl doesn't care about your history,
并不在乎你们的过去
Nor do her terrified parents.
家长只想看到女儿活着回来
They just want their baby back alive.
他在哪  长官
Where is he, sir?
在那边跟父母谈话
He's over there talking to the parents.
我是蒙哥马利
Montgomery.
拜托  有什么要求尽管提
Yeah, please. Whatever you need.
失陪一下
Excuse me.
-你好  凯特  -你好  威尔
- Hello, Kate. - Hello, Will.
回来多久了
How long have you been back?
几个月
A couple months.
波士顿不好吗
Something wrong with Boston?
心血来潮而已
Fresh lobster gets old fast.
看来你过的不错
You look good.
谢谢  感觉不错
Thanks. I feel good.
索伦森探员  这位是理查德·卡塞尔
Agent Sorenson, this is Richard Castle.
著名的小说家
The famous novelist.
揭露丑恶罪行
Writer of wrongs.
蒙哥马利队长跟我说了你们的小安排
So captain Montgomery filled me in on your little arrangement.
只要不妨碍调查
I have no problem with it
我没什么意见
As long as it doesn't interfere with the investigation.
不用担心  我不会出声
Oh, don't worry about me. Quiet as a mouse.
安吉拉·坎德拉  两岁
Angela Candela, 2 years old,
今天早上七点半到八点之间被绑架
Abducted this morning between 7:30 and 8:00 a.M.
当时父母在家
Parents were home at the time.
父母都在家  怎么还会被绑架
How do you get abducted when your parents are home?
大约七点爸爸叫孩子起床
Dad got up with the kid about 7:00,
妈妈还没起床
Let the mom sleep in.
他把安吉拉放到电视机前
He planted Angela in front of the tube
给她一罐果汁和一些麦片
With a juice box and some cereal,
然后去他的画室工作去了
Then headed into his art studio.
显然  他是个画家
Obviously, he's a painter.
他就这样把孩子扔在一边
He just left his kid?
至少他听得到一点声响吧
Did he hear anything at least?
他当时正听着Ipod
He was listening to his ipod.
没个做爸爸的样子
Nothing like a little quality time with daddy.
《灵书妙探》  第一季第九集
Castle S01E09
发现她不见了  我就到处去找
When I couldn't find her, I looked everywhere for her,
然后我看到了打开的窗户
And then I saw the window.
锁从外面被撬开了
The lock was jimmied from the outside.
我跑到外面找
I- I ran outside. I looked for her.
坎德拉先生  你们住在一楼
Mr. Candela, you live on a ground floor apartment
窗户正对着巷子
With windows facing the alleyway.
一般人们都会装栅栏
Most people have bars.
本来打算装的  只是
We were going to. We just--
我没时间
I never got around to it.
我们认为这些泥土是从外面带进来的
We think the dirt's from the outside.
这种事情怎么会发上在我们自己家里
How could this happen in our own home?
看来疑犯是从窗户爬进来
So our suspect climbed in through the window,
抓了安吉拉  然后从后门走出去
Grabbed Angela and probably walked out the back door.
就这样吗
Just like that?
我们已经把她的照片发出去
We have her photo on the wires
并向出入境管理局和州际地区发出安珀警报
And are issuing an amber alert to the port authority and the tri-State area.
我让我的人查一查
I'll have my guys run
有案底的强奸犯和入室盗窃犯
Any registered sex offenders and residential burglaries.
孩子的父母呢
What about the parents?
他们能想到哪些人
Anyone they can think of?
没有  两个人暂时还提供不了什么情况
No, not that either of them can think straight right now.
情况继续恶化的话  他们就没机会想了
This thing goes south, they'll never think straight again.
索伦森探员
Agent Sorenson?
电话在那边  装上监听器
The phone's over there. Get a tap on it.
这件案子会有好结果的
This one will end better.
我保证
I promise.
六个月
Six months.
六个月什么
Six months what?
我们交往了六个月
We dated for six months.
我又没问你
I didn't ask.
我知道
Yeah, I know.
你只不过没有喊出来而已
You were not asking very loudly.
感觉自己像绝地武士一样有心灵感应
I know. I'm like a jedi like that.
你们怎么认识的
So how'd you meet?
一件绑架案  一个六岁的男孩
Kidnapping. A 6-Year-Old boy.
结果呢
How'd it end?
抓到了罪犯
We got the guy.
父母的情况了解多少
What do we got on the parents?
泰丽莎和阿尔弗雷德·坎德拉
Theresa and Alfred Candela--
两年前结婚  生有一女  就是安吉拉·坎德拉
Married ten years, one child-- Angela Candela.
对不起
Sorry.
对不起  你的领带吓了我一跳
Sorry about that. Tie took me a little by surprise.
好吧  说明一下
Okay, get it all out.
这是我女友送的
This is a gift from my girlfriend.
女友
Girlfriend?
今天是我们相识两周纪念日
Today's our 2-Week anniversary.
两周  算纸婚还是丝婚呢
Two weeks. Is that the paper or the silk?
我觉得是鞭婚
I believe it's the whipped.
-说得好  -行了  行了  别说了
- Good one. - Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
女儿安吉拉·坎德拉  两岁  领养的
One child-- Angela candela, age 2, adopted.
-领养的  -是的  两年前领养
- Adopted? - Yeah, two years ago.
母亲泰丽莎  是凯勒·斯丹顿的财务经理
Mom-- Theresa, she's a fund manager at Keller Stanton.
父亲是个三流的画家
Dad's a small-time artist,
其作品只在切尔西的格雷森画廊展出一次
Shows at the Greyson Gallery in Chelsea once in a while.
邻居说  他在家带孩子
Neighbor says he stays home with the kid.
这里有张名单
All right, here's a list of all the people
都是可能进入他们家的人
Who had access to the apartment--
保姆  清洁工  公寓管理员
Babysitters, cleaning lady, super.
把这些人与本地在册的强奸犯作个对比
Let's cross-Reference that with any registered sex offenders in the area,
看看是否有恋童癖
See if anyone had a thing for little girls.
你认为可能是公寓内部有偷窥狂吗
You're thinking that some creepy-crawly probably scouted from the inside?
父亲说今早做的事跟往常一样
Well, the father said what he did this morning was part of a routine.
所以要么是罪犯走运
So either somebody got lucky,
要么是对情况了如指掌
Or they already knew it.
好  我们马上到
Yeah, we'll be right there.
似乎不是偷窥狂
Looks like it wasn't a creepy-crawler after all.
坎德拉家刚接到一个勒索电话
Candelas just got a ransom call.
喂
Hello?
你们的女儿在我手上
We have your daughter.
求你了  她只是个孩子  求你不要伤害她
Please, she's just a child. Please don't hurt her.
那就看你们怎么做了
Whether we hurt her is up to you.
你们的所为将决定她的生死
Whether she lives is up to you.
想要你们的女儿吗
You want your daughter?
拿75万来  给你们24小时
We want $750,000. You have 24 hours.
我要跟她说话  我要知道她是否没事
I want to speak to her. I want to know she's safe.
他们用的是网络电话
They used an internet voice-over-I.P. Service.
就是说无法追踪
Meaning it's untraceable.
你们拿得出75万吗
Can you raise the 750?
75万是我们的全部家当
It-- It's everything we have.
只要能让安吉拉回来  我们会给他的
If it means getting Angela back, we'll pay.
那你们就赶紧开始筹钱吧
Then you should start getting your financial records together.
坎德拉太太  有没有什么人能帮你
Mrs. Candela, is there anyone that you know
会计师或你们公司的人
That can help you-- An accountant or maybe someone at your firm?
妮娜能帮我们
Nina could help.
-妮娜是谁  -我妹妹  她是注册会计师
- Nina? - My sister. She's a C.P.A.
但是就算我们把钱给了他们
But even if we give them the money,
又怎能保证女儿能回来
How can we be sure we'll get her back?
你们要抱有希望
You have to have hope.
你们要想象女儿能安然无恙的踏入家门
You have to imagine your little girl walking through that front door safe and sound.
现在你们的女儿需要你们
Your daughter needs you right now.
需要你们充满信心  还要坚强
She needs you to have faith, to be strong.
这种案子你办的很多吗  我是说绑架案
You do this a lot-- Kidnappings?
似乎你知道说话的套路
You seem to know what to say.
说什么不重要
It's not about what you say.
重要的是控制局面  控制情绪
It's about controlling the situation, controlling the emotions.
你要求你的前女友参与此案
You requested your ex-girlfriend for the task force.
这可不像是控制情绪的表现
That doesn't indicate to me a control of your emotions.
我请贝克特来是因为她是纽约最好的警探
I requested Beckett because she's the best in the city.
不是因为你想再见她一次吗
Not because you wanted to see her again?
你呢  卡塞尔
How about you, Castle?
你已经写了  大概20本畅销书了吧
You've written, what, 20 best sellers?
26本  不过这不算什么
Well, 26, but who's countin'?
怎么想起以真警探为原型呢
Why the sudden need to shadow a real detective?
电视上戴墨镜的警察太老套了
Well, the ones on tv seem oddly fixated on their sunglasses.
从纽约警署里众多大腹便便的秃顶警察里
So with all the fat, balding detectives in the NYPD,
你就那么巧找到她这个原型
You just happen to end up shadowing her.
肯定是缘分吧
It must be fate.
应该是吧
Must be.
坎德拉夫妇列出了财务清单
Candelas have pulled their financials.
她妹妹妮娜马上就到
Her sister's on the way.
电话记录有发现吗
Anything on the transcripts?
很明显赎金要求很特别
It's clear the ransom demand has significance.
绑匪很清楚坎德拉夫妇的家底
Kidnappers make an issue about knowing what the Candelas have.
他们说这是全部的钱
They said it's everything they have.
绑匪对他们了如指掌  熟悉他们的经济状况
Whoever made the demand knows them well enough to know exactly what they're worth.
怎么样
How does it look?
警探  索伦森探员  这是我妹妹妮娜
Detective, agent Sorenson, this is my sister Nina.
可以办到  明早我们就把股票卖掉
It's doable. We'll market the stocks tomorrow morning.
还得把退休金和养老金都提出来
We'll have to wipe out the retirement account and both pensions,
这样你们就得付罚金
And you'll have to pay penalties.
不管多大代价  我不在乎
I don't care. Whatever it takes.
他心情紧张的时候就画画
He paints when he's stressed.
画卖的好吗
Does he sell much?
卖了一些吧
Some.
言过其实了
That's generous.
不好意思
Sorry.
干嘛问这个
Why do you ask?
据我所知有养老金的艺术家可不多
I don't know many artists with their own pension account.
是特丽萨替他开的户
Theresa set up the account for him
他想给自己和安吉拉留点什么
So he'd have something for him and Angela, you know,
-以防万一  -想问问
- If something-- - Tell me--
坎德拉太太
Mrs. Candela,
我们认为赎金的具体数目
We think the specificity of the amount of the ransom demand
说明了绑匪很了解你们的财务状况
Suggests the kidnappers had knowledge of your finances.
你们有没有跟人结仇
Was there anyone who might've had a grudge against you
或者身边有人最近缺钱呢
Or maybe someone close to you who need the money now?
不会有人做这种事
No one who would do something like this.
道格·艾勒斯会不会呢
What about Doug Ellers?
谁是道格·艾勒斯
Who's Doug ellers?
以前的同事  可我想不出来...
Someone I used to work with, but no, I can't imagine--
那他临走时对你说的那些话
What about those messages he left you at work?
记得吗  你还向人力资源部反应过
Remember, you filed those complaints with H.R.?
我自己知道  阿佛雷德
I know what happened, Alfred.
坎德拉太太  我知道这不好受
Mrs. Candela, I know how hard this is.
你难受我也理解
It's understandable to get frustrated.
不过我们需要了解所有情况
But please, we need to know everything.
艾勒斯负责一个资产管理小组
Ellers ran an asset management group.
这组表现不好  我开除了他
They weren't performing, so I let him go.
他威胁过你吗
Did he ever threaten you?
他把婚姻破裂怪在我头上
Well, he blamed me for his divorce.
他说我炒了他  所以妻子抛弃了他  而且
He said his wife left him because I fired him, and...
而且什么
And what?
而且她把两个孩子也带走了
And she took his two kids.
在哪儿找到他的
Where'd you find him?
他正排队赌外围呢
In line at off-Track betting.
紧急事务组查过他家
E.S.U. Just hit his apartment.
-没找到孩子  -这可不妙
- No trace of the kid. - That's not good.
审审看吧
Pressure interview?
-我先来  -好的
- I'll take the lead. - Yeah.
不行
No.
他可以的  威尔
He'll be fine, will.
凯特  我不管你有多崇拜他
Kate, I don't care how big a fan of his you are,
他不能进去
He doesn't come in the room.
好吧  没关系
Fine. That's fine.
不过我打听一下
Uh, just for the record, though,
她有多崇拜我
How big a fan is she?
得了吧  卡塞尔
Come on, Castle.
跟我去观察室看吧
Come watch from the bleachers with us,
见识一下联调局的厉害
See how the feebies do it.
艾勒斯先生  我是凯特·贝克特探长
Mr. Ellers, detective Kate Beckett,
纽约警局
NYPD.
我是索伦森特工  联调局的
Special agent sorenson, FBI.
最后一次见特丽萨·坎德拉是什么时候
When was your last contact with Theresa Candela?
特丽萨·坎德拉  怎么啦
Theresa Candela? Wh-Wh-What's going on?
问什么答什么
Just answer the question.
她说我什么了
What did she say about me?
咱们还是说说
Let's talk about...
你对她说过什么吧
What you said to her.
我奉献给你六年  六年啊
I gave you six years of my life. Six years!
是我赚钱养活了你那个破部门
My profits built your whole damn division.
可你现在落井下石
And now you want to bend me over?
赶我出门  会有报应的  特丽萨
You want to cut me out? Well, karma's a bitch, Theresa.
你害我家破人亡  我会以牙还牙
You burnt down my house. I'm gonna burn yours down.
这是你三个月前的留言
You left that three months ago,
你太太刚离开的时候
Just after your wife left.
没错  怎么了
Yeah? So?
每个字都是真的
Every word of it's true.
这是骚扰
It's harassment.
那又怎么样  她要告我吗
Oh, what, is she gonna press charges now?
对  绑架  袭击  非法入室
Yeah, kidnapping, assault, breaking and entering.
你他妈胡说些什么
What the hell are you talking about?
今早安吉拉·坎德拉被绑架了
Somebody kidnapped Angela Candela this morning.
什么  绑架
What? Kidnapped?
伤害别人的孩子
Hurting someone else's child
并不能追回失去的东西
isn't the way to get back your own.
不  不  不  这种事我不干
No, no, no. This is not me.
虽然不待见特丽萨
Theresa may not be my favorite person,
可我绝不会去伤害一个孩子
But I would never harm a child.
你前妻大概不会这么想
Your ex-Wife wasn't so sure.
离婚判决书上对你提出
According to your divorce papers,
暴力指控...
there are allegations of violence--
我前妻不过是想要钱  就这样
My ex-Wife was looking for a payday. That's all.
你也是想要钱  对吗  艾勒斯先生
You're not looking for a payday, are you, Mr. Ellers?
你们抓错人了
You have the wrong guy.
查查他  早上在哪儿  有没有证人
Run him down-- Where he was all morning, who can vouch.
明显不是他
Pretty clear it wasn't him.
你还会读心术啊
You a mind reader, too?
得了吧  如果是他
Come on, if he was your guy,
他会掩饰对特丽萨的厌恶
He'd be downplaying his feelings for Theresa,
而不会这么外露
Not wearing them on his sleeve.
写几本畅销书不代表你成了犯罪学家
Couple dozen best sellers doesn't make you a criminologist.
那也不用气象学家告诉我天是蓝色的
I also don't need a weatherman to tell me that the sky is blue.
看在上帝的份上
Oh, for god sakes.
你俩就不能屏弃前嫌吗
Why don't you both just drop your pants and get it over with?
我同意
I'm game.
其实你俩都对  或许不是他
The fact is, you're both right. He probably didn't do it.
可现在孩子危在旦夕  必须要查清楚
But when a child's life is at stake, we have to be sure.
我们必须查证我们想当然的事
We have to question everything we think we know.
你们看住艾勒斯
You guys keep Ellers on eyes
直到查明他早上的所有活动
Until we can trace every second of his morning.
威尔  你和我回坎德拉家
Will, you and I are going back to the Candelas'.
查清他们身边所有的人
We're gonna profile all of their associates.
我做什么
What should I do?
回家
I need you to go home.
好吧
Okay.
如果有需要  给我打电话
But if you need me, call...
就算闲聊也行
Even if it's just to talk.
托德  宝贝
Todd, honey...
我非常非常需要你
I really, really need you
专心调整你的创造力
Focus on calibrating your creative energy.
至于创造力
Now by creative energy,
是指什么呢
What do I mean?
指的是你力量的源泉
I mean the source of your power.
力量的源泉  托德  就源于你自己
The source of your power, Todd, is you.
妈  你怎么能
How do you, mother.
你好  你  你回来了
Hello. You're... You're here.
我刚在我的办公室里上完课
I'm just finishing up a session in my office.
看到您的办公室里有我著作的封面
I'm so flattered you have my framed book covers
我真开心
In your office.
心灵指导师不可居功自傲
Well, a coach can never be too proud.
卡塞尔先生  谢谢您
Mr. Castle, I just wanted to thank you
感谢您能开诚布公的坦言
For being so honest about your struggle
自己长期与灵感枯竭斗争的心路历程
With persistent and chronic writer's block.
您说什么
Excuse me?
托德是很有进取心的作家
Well, Todd is an aspiring novelist,
所以我给他讲述了
So I shared with him
你在逆境中成长的光荣事迹
your inspiring tale of triumph over adversity.
是嘛  我还真是勇猛
Well, how courageous of me.
祝你好运  托德
Good luck, Todd.
谢谢
Thanks.
我要订全年课程
I'll take the year-Long package.
英明果断  老弟  对你有益
Way to be decisive, kiddo. Good for you.
-下周见  -谢谢您
- I'll see you next week. - Thank you.
-见到您很高兴  -记住  你就是你
- Nice to meet you. - And remember, you is who you is.
你不成仁  谁成仁呢
And if you ain't who you is, who is you?
这么多年的演员
Well, nice to see all those years
总算没白当
As an actress have really paid off.
专心调整你的创造力
"Focus on calibrating your creative energies"?
我会让你明白的
I'll have you know,
托德天资聪慧  需要引导
Todd is a very bright spirit in need of direction.
妈  你造我的谣已经够糟了
Mother, it's bad enough that you're slandering me.
难道还要挤占我的办公室
Do you have to commandeer my office
搞你这套知心大姐游戏吗
To do your new age coddle session?
理查德  你该不会想让我
Richard, you can't expect me
在曼哈顿租间办公室吧
To pay Manhattan rates for office space.
那这里如何
Well, how about this?
史上最佳位置
You cannot beat this location.
饮料和刀叉都是触手可及
Proximity to beverages and sharp utensils.
宝贝  作为你的生活导师
Sweetheart, as your life coach,
我奉劝你少听心里唱反调的那个声音
I have to urge you to say nay to your inner naysayer.
我管这叫玛莎主义
I call that a Martha-Ism.
你连我父亲是谁都没清楚
How is it that you don't know who my father is,
也没搞清前夫如何偷光你的钱
You don't know how your ex-Husband stole all your money,
怎么指导别人的生活呢
Yet you are giving life coaching advice?
失败乃成功之母
Mistakes are the building blocks of wisdom.
这也是玛莎主义
A Martha-Ism.
更何况  弗洛伊德虽然是个瘾君子
Besides, Freud was an addict.
也没耽误他帮助别人
Didn't stop him from helping people.
可惜的是  听了妈妈
Sadly, faced with his mother's...
无懈可击的狡辩
Twisted yet unimpeachable logic,
理查德·卡塞尔脑袋炸了
Richard Castle' s head exploded.
是嘛
Ah, well.
怎么今天回家这么早
So why are you home so early?
主要是想歇一歇
Well, thought I'd take a little breather.
正在忙一个绑架案
Working on a, uh, kidnapping case.
一个小姑娘被绑了
A little girl.
难怪你板着个脸
No wonder you're so surly.
可怜的家长  自己的孩子被人抢走
Those poor parents, having a child ripped away...
真没法想象他们的感受
I can't imagine how they must feel.
阿丽克西斯在家吗
Is Alexis home?
在楼上呢
She's upstairs.
我迫切需要一个拥抱
I'm feeling a deep-Seated need for a hug.
完全理解
Perfectly understandable.
毕竟  我们都是豆荚里的豆子
After all, we are pod-Mates.
也是玛莎主义  我称之为豆荚纽带
Another martha-Ism. I call it the peapod bond--
就是那种父母跟孩子之间的纽带
You know, the bond that exists between parent and child--
你和我  你和阿丽克西斯
You and me, you and Alexis.
不管喜不喜欢  我们都是豆荚里的豆子
We're all peas in a pod, and whether we like it or not,
只要有孩子  就是豆荚里的豆子
Everyone who's ever had a child is in the pod forever.
豆荚纽带
The peapod bond.
阿丽克西斯  谢谢你  妈
Alexis! Thank you, mother.
我的指导费就从租金里扣吧
I'll deduct my session fee from your rent.
或许你应该考虑订购全年课程
You might want to consider the year-long package.
价钱好商量
It's a bargain!
这什么意思
What was that for?
只是豆荚问题
Just a peapod thing.
让奶奶解释会给你听
Gram will explain.
你好
Hey.
你也好  来点吗
Hey, yourself. Want some?
好啊  谢谢
Yeah, thanks.
我的人刚才说
So I just got word from my guys,
艾勒斯那边没得可查了
And Ellers is a dead end.
第62东大街天国餐厅的老板证实了
The owner over at Paradise Diner on East 62nd vouched
他今早照常在他店里吃荷包蛋
That he was having his usual poached eggs this morning.
也太简单了  是吧
Would have been too easy, right?
或者说  过于简单
Or over easy?
听起来像卡塞尔的语气
That's like something Castle would say.
你喜欢他
You like him.
不  我只是...
No, I just, um...
说不好
I don't know.
我觉得他很有趣
I think he's interesting.
看来你们还没..
So you're not...
走到一起吗  没有
Together? No.
我本想给你打电话
I meant to call.
几十次电话都拿起来了
Must have picked up the phone a dozen times.
我明白  你本想做很多事
Yeah, I know. You meant to do a lot of things.
所以就走了  记得吗
That's why you left, remember?
当时波士顿那里对我来说机会难得
Boston was a great opportunity.
我没否认
I'm not saying that it wasn't.
我只是说  你当时做出了选择
I'm just saying, it was a choice...
而我并非你的选择
That didn't include me.
你本可以一起去
You could have come.
去了干什么呢
And then done what?
去波士顿当警察  然后你又搬到凤凰城
Join the Boston P.D., and then you have to move to Phoenix
然后克里夫兰  然后又回到这儿吗
And then Cleveland, and then you're back here?
我是说  你我都清楚那是什么样的日子
I mean, we both know what that life is all about.
可这样我也一直想你
Didn't stop me from missing you,
想我们
Missing us.
公园里度过的那些星期天
Sundays in the park...
还有洛克菲勒中心滑稽的溜冰鞋
Those ridiculous neon ice skates at Rockefeller Center.
我跟你说  那些溜冰鞋很棒的
I will have you know that those ice skates are awesome.
冰鞋并不是重点
It wasn't the skates.
威尔  我
Will, I--I'm...
我还以为警察和特工不共戴天呢
Oh! I thought cops and feds hated each other.
人说正义永不灭  我想我知道原因了
They say justice never sleeps. I think I know why.
-我们只是  -大家都是成年人
- We were just, uh-- - Being consenting adults.
我无意评判
I'm not judging.
我记得让你回家了呀
I thought I told you to go home.
我确实回家了
I did go home,
不过我母亲提醒了我一件要紧的事
But then my mother told me something that couldn't wait.
你和你妈一起住
You live with your mother?
没错  很明显我们都是豆荚里的豆子
Yeah, apparently, we're peas in a pod.
重点是  安吉拉是收养的
But the important point is, Angela is adopted.
所以呢
So?
所以在送出孩子之前
So prior to giving up her baby,
生母是要了解收养家庭的情况
The birth mother would have been given background on the Candelas,
尤其是抚养能力
Specifically their ability to support the child.
你是指财政情况
Knowledge of their finances.
实话说  凯特
Really, Kate,
我们还得费时听南希·珠尔[电影《少女神探》主角]的意见吗
We're gonna waste time on the insights of Nancy Drew here?
这算侮辱吗
Is that supposed to be an insult?
南希·珠尔可是破了所有的案件
Because Nancy Drew solved every case.
听着  我来引用一下这句话
Look, okay, and I'm quoting here,
孩子危在旦夕时
"When a child's life is at stake,
必须要查清楚
We have to be sure,
我们必须查证我们想当然的事
Which means we have to question everything we think we know."
我当时在上高中
I was a junior in high school.
能拿孩子怎么办呢
What was I gonna do with a baby?
已经过去两年了  戈麦斯小姐
It's been two years, Miss Gomez.
两年的时间足够让你
Two years is still a long time
好好反思自己16岁时做的决定了
To think about a decision you made when you were 16.
你们找我来干什么  要谈什么呀
What am I doing here? What is this about?
我们要谈谈你的孩子
We're talking about the baby
还有你把孩子送人之后的悔意
and your regretting your decision.
悔意
My decision?
我没有后悔过
I don't regret my decision.
那你为什么还想找她
Then why did you try to find her?
你在说什么啊
What are you talking about?
这是数月前你在领养机构填写的申请书
This is a petition that you filed with the adoption agency a couple of months ago.
要求了解安吉拉的养父母
It's a form requesting the identity of the adoptive parents of Angela.
-有你的签名  -我没签过
- A signed form. - No.
-那不是我签的  -露西娅  我不是
- That's not my signature. - Lucia, I'm not--
真的不是  给  你自己看
No, really. Look, you can see for yourself.
那不是我的签名
That's not my signature.
怎么了  出什么事了吗
Why? What's going on?
她怎么了
What happened to her?
她还好吗
Is she okay?
你家里有人反对放弃这个孩子吗
Did anyone in your family object to you giving up your baby?
没有  我妈妈还一直帮我
No, no one. My-- My mom even helped me with it.
孩子的生父吗
And the father?
胡安
Juan?
我怀孕时他在伊拉克
He was in Iraq when I had her,
但我们谈过的
But we talked about it.
他没什么意见
He was cool.
你确定吗
Are you sure about that?
他还在伊拉克吗
He still in iraq?
不  几个月前回来了
No, he got back a couple months ago.
胡安·雷斯特雷波
Juan Restrepo?
纽约警局  我们想问你一些...
NYPD. We'd like to ask you some--
快点  快  站住
Go, go, go, go! Hey!
不许动  举起手来
Freeze! Hands up!
不许动
Freeze!
举起手来
Keep your hands up!
趴下  听到没有
On the ground. On the ground!
趴下
Hit the ground!
住在我们那里的人
Look, in my neighborhood,
看见警察都这种反应
When you see a cop, that's what you do.
怎么  好警察还是烂特工
What? No, uh, good cop/bad fed?
那家伙曾在海湾地区服役两届
The guy did two tours in the Gulf.
我过去会惹火他的
I go over there, he'd turn it into a pissing match.
但是凯特却懂得接近别人
But Kate, she's got a way of sneaking up on people.
你是说就像昨晚一样吗
You mean like last night?
难以置信
Can you believe this?
那家伙以车内装饰为生
Dude details cars for a living.
我还以为他会把自己的车好好收拾下
You'd think he'd have a little more pride in his ride.
我只是想说
I'm just saying,
吻得够深情的
It looked like quite a kiss.
-卡塞尔  吃醋了  -我
- You jealous, Castle? - Me?
没有  但是你不得不承认  我正中要害
No, but you have to admit... I was right.
你就是在吃醋  因为我勾引她
You are jealous... That I hooked her.
有什么好吃醋的  你又搞不定她
What's there to be jealous of? You couldn't reel her in.
我们走着瞧
We'll see about that.
露西娅怀孕时  我只有18岁
I was 18 when Lucia got pregnant.
六个月之后我被调走了
Six months in, I got deployed.
再也没机会见她
I never even had the chance to see her.
但你签了那请愿书
But you signed the adoption papers.
在那边我见到了很多孩子
You know, when you're over there, you see so many kids.
我只是
I just...
只是想知道孩子过得很好
I need to know she was okay.
我就用露西娅的名字填了表
I- I filled out the form, and I put Lucia's name instead.
-地址给你了  -对  那人同情我
- You got an address. - Yeah, dude felt bad for me.
他参加了第一次海湾战争
He was over there, too, in Gulf One,
而且他只失去了一条胳膊
And he only lost an arm.
你失去了什么
And what did you lose?
土炸弹炸了我的输送车
An I.E.D. Hit my humvee.
炸飞了车的底板
The shrapnel tore through the floor.
医生说这辈子我不可能有自己的孩子了
The doc says I'm never gonna have kids of my own,
所以
So...
是的  我是有地址  还去看了我女儿
Yeah, I got an address, and I went to go see my daughter.
然后你就绑架她  还向她养父母索要赎金
So you kidnap her and you ask her adoptive parents for money?
等等  绑架  她被绑架了吗
Wait, "kidnap her"? She was kidnapped?
你觉得我会干出这种事
And you think I did that?
我只是想知道她过得好不好
All I ever wanted to know was that she was okay!
她还好吗
Is she?!
生父的话核实过了
Yo. Birth dad? His story checks out.
豪华轿车公司昨天让他去装饰车队了
Limo Company had him doing their fleet yesterday.
我不管  他既有动机又有机会
I don't care. He had motive and opportunity.
他的动机就是父亲的本能
His motive was the instinct of fatherhood.
要是真是他干的  他会一直陪着她的
If he took her, he'd have been with her,
而不是去干他那薪水卑微的工作
Not at some $12-An-Hour detailing job.
那不重要
Doesn't matter.
我要让鉴证科彻底搜查他的房子
I want E.S.U. On his place.
不是他干的  威尔
It's not him, Will.
我们折腾半天  一无所获
We're at square freakin' one, and we've got nothing.
你可以让鉴证科去任何地方
You can send E.S.U. wherever you want,
但这次我不想办砸
But I'm not losing this one.
她为什么说"不想办砸"
What did she mean, "not losing this one"?
我们上次的案子
The case we worked.
凶手不是抓到了吗
I thought you got the guy.
是抓到了  不过
We did, but...
孩子死了
The kid was already dead.
我是索伦森
Sorenson.
马上就到
On my way.
绑匪又打电话要赎金了
Another call about the ransom.
他们要75捆百元现钞
They asked for 75 packs of hundreds,
不能连号  不能是饵钱
Randomized serial numbers and warned against bait money,
不能带防盗染色包或追踪器
Dye packs and trackers.
好像很清楚你们的办案手法
Sounds like they know your playbook.
他们对包的样式和颜色
They were detailed down to the make,
要求的很具体
Model and color of the backpack.
送钱的指令呢
Drop instructions?
还在等电话
We wait for their call.
好吧  我们把钱整好
All right, let's get the money set,
准备交赎金
Be ready to make the drop.
他们为什么没说钱送到哪里
Why didn't they tell us where to bring the money?
他们在试探  这很正常
They're testing you. It's not unusual.
这就意味着交赎金前
Which means before we make the drop,
我们也得试探一下他们
We'll need to test them.
证实安吉拉确实在他们手上并且毫发无伤
We'll need proof that they have Angela and that she's okay.
他们要是不配合呢
What if they don't give any?
-他们拒绝怎么办  -你怎么能这么想
- What if they refuse? - How can you think that?
-我只是说  -什么  你觉得她死了吗
- I'm just saying-- - What, you think she's dead?
-不  当然不是  -我应该起床的
- No, of course not. - I should've gotten up.
不该让你来照看她
I shouldn't have let you watch her.
别告诉我你想说什么
Don't tell me what to say!
你看看  阿尔弗雷德  就为了这玩意
Tell me, Alfred, was it worth it?!
这破画顶的上我们的女儿吗
Was it worth our little girl?!
我  我的
Oh! Oh, my...
坎德拉太太
Mrs. Candela?
泰丽莎
Theresa...
你不能向恐惧屈服
You can't give in to your fear.
你和你丈夫都没错
Neither you nor your husband is responsible for what happened.
来吧
Come on.
记住了  没有证据就不给钱  我们得明确这个
Remember, no proof, no money. We need to be firm on that.
好了吗  接电话
Okay? Here we go.
喂
Hello.
听好了
Listen carefully.
出任何差错  你女儿就死定了
Any deviation, and your daughter dies.
我明白
I understand.
送钱的人不能是警察  把钱放下就走
A civilian, not a cop, must make the drop,
不然我们就撕票
Or we kill the girl.
有警察或者联调局的人
We see police or FBI,
她就死定了
And she dies.
钱准备好了吗
Do you have the money?
好了  按你说的  75万
Yes. 750, like you said.
放在背包里
Put it in the backpack
一号大街和四十七号大街之间
And bring it to the northeast corner
路口的东北角
of 1st avenue and 47th.
那有一个邮筒
There's a mailbox there
下面粘着手机
With a cell phone taped underneath.
你到了我们再发信息告诉你下一步
We'll text further instructions once you're there.
拿到钱以后
When we have the money,
我们会打电话告诉你孩子在哪里
Then we'll call with the girl's location.
叫他证明安吉拉没事
Ask for proof that Angela's okay.
我得确定我女儿没事再给你们钱
You won't get any money until I know my little girl is okay.
妈妈
Mama?
宝贝
Hi, sweetheart.
给你一小时
You have one hour.
他们拿到钱就不会留活口了
Once they get paid, there's no incentive to keep her alive,
我去交赎金
So I'll make the drop.
我们会在邮箱周围一个街区内
Figure, we'll place our people
部署警员
at a 1-Block radius from the mailbox.
不行
No.
他们说了警察不能去
They said no cops.
没事的  我以前干过
It's okay. I've done this before.
他们不会发现我是联调局的探员
And they won't know I'm an FBI agent.
发现了怎么办
And if they do?
坎德拉先生  我们得确保一切顺利
Mr. Candela, we need this to go as smoothly as possible.
她是我女儿
She's my daughter,
所以我们得按他们说的办
And we're gonna follow their instructions to the letter.
他们说了不要警察
They said no cops.
听着  我是她爸爸
Look, I'm her father,
所以我一定可以的
And I can do this.
听清楚了吗
Do I make myself clear?
我们不能派他去
No way we can send the father.
他太激动了  会出乱子的
Too many things could go wrong. He's too emotional.
还有别的选择吗
What choice do we have?
-我  -什么
- Me. - What?
我不是警察
I'm not a cop.
当然也不那么激动
I'm certainly not emotional.
不  绝对不行
No. Absolutely not.
纽约警察局已经跟我签了免责协议
The NYPD already has a signed waiver from me,
我不想提这个
And I don't like saying this,
不过我们已经没时间了
But you're running out of time.
卡塞尔说的没错
Castle's right.
你不是认真的吧
You can't be serious.
他之前和我一起办过案
He's been with me on cases before.
他能顶得住压力
He's good under pressure.
所以他是最佳人选
And he's our best shot.
通常这个时候
Okay, so this is usually the part
我都会问当事人是否考虑清楚了
Where I ask if you've thought this through,
不过我记得你从来不三思而后行
And then I rembered, you don't think things through.
你的手真凉  冰棍一样
Cold hands, cold hands.
卡塞尔  这些人很危险
These people are dangerous, Castle.
你得保持警惕  集中精神
You need to stay alert and focused.
警惕  集中精神  遵命
Alert and focused, got it.
你能不能
Maybe if--Maybe if
能不能搓搓手呢
you just rubbed 'em together for a second.
等等  警惕和什么来着
Wait, wait. Alert and what?
开玩笑的
I'm just kidding.
-好了  -多谢
- You're good to go. - Thanks.
不会有事的
Hey, it's gonna be okay.
听着  关于昨晚在厨房发生的事
Look, about... Last night, what happened in the kitchen,
-我只是  -不不不
- I- I just-- - Oh, listen,
你不用解释
You don't need to explain that.
-那是  -不用吗
- That's-- - I don't?
除非你想
Unless you want to.
我只是想到  你知道的
Uh, no, you know, I ju-- I just figured,
对于那个角色妮基·希特
For the character, for Nikki Heat--
你  我觉得我比你想象得
Yeah, you-- I think-- I think understand Nikki Heat
更了解妮基·希特
Better than you think I do.
小心点  好吗
Be careful, okay?
莫非你是在关心我的人身安全
Do I detect actual concern for my well-Being?
你要是搞砸了我就杀了你
Screw this up, and I'll kill you.
这才像你
That's more like it.
我看到目标了  报告完毕
Okay, I have eyes on the target. Over.
你们听到了吗
Are you reading me?
不用听
We don't have to read you.
我们能看见你  给我闭上嘴集中精神
We can see you. Now shut up and focus.
收到  清楚的明白
Roger that. Five by five.
他很有个性
He's quite a guy.
但愿他知道你是他忠实的粉丝
If he only knew how big a fan you really are.
是啊  他不会知道的
Yeah, well, he's not going to know.
你没告诉他  为了得到他的签名
You never told him how you stood in line for an hour
你排队站了一个小时
Just to get your book signed...
他的小说陪你度过你母亲死后那段时光
How his novels got you through your mother's death?
有什么事你不记吗
Is there anything you don't remember?
只要是关于你的都记住
Not when it comes to you.
感觉就像迈克找到了藏在厕所后面的枪
I feel like Michael finding the gun taped behind the toilet.
恐怕你得让莱恩和埃斯波西托退回去
You might want to tell Ryan and Esposito to hang back.
他们发了条信息说"我们在监视你"
They just sent a text. It says, "we're watching you."
可能只是唬人的
It could be just a ruse.
不像
Nope.
他们刚又发了条信息过来
They just sent another one.
上面说"你穿着黑色雨衣"
It says, "you're wearing a black raincoat."
没错  他们是能看到你  但计划不变
Okay, so they can see you. That doesn't change anything.
让他别胡闹
Tell him to stop fooling around.
那有用吗
Like that'll help.
又有信息了
Okay...
上面说"穿过马路
It says, "cross the street,
然后向西走到东47大街"
And head west on east 47th."
向左走  对吗
That's left, right?
是的
Right.
是  往右  还是往左
Right, right? Or right, left?
-往左  -左
- Left  - Left.
"一号大街1201号"  就在前面
"1201 1st." That's just ahead.
收到  我们看到他了
Got it. We see him.
他们让我把包放在擦鞋摊那儿
They want me to leave the bag at the shoeshine stand
然后退出去
And exit out the side.
好了  我在摊位这儿了
All right. I'm at the stand.
让他把包放下
Then have him make the drop.
卡塞尔  放下包
Castle, leave the bag.
把包放下然后离开
Make the drop and walk away.
进来了  还没发现目标
Coming in. Don't have him yet.
放下了  我出来了
I just left it. I'm headed out.
埃斯波西托  莱恩  发现什么了吗
Esposito, Ryan. .. You got eyes?
我看到擦鞋摊了
I see the shoeshine stand.
等一下  我看到那个包了
Wait. I got the backpack.
亚洲男性  长头发  我抓到他了
Asian male... Long hair. I got him, I got him!
那个女孩儿在哪儿  安吉拉在哪儿
Where's the girl? Where's Angela?
什么女孩
What girl?
我不知道你在说什么
I don't know what you're talking about!
莱恩  莱恩
Ryan! Ryan!
绑匪们就像在做广告
The kidnappers posted an ad on Craigslist
说这是为YouTube做的艺术作品
And said that this was a performance art piece for YouTube.
那儿有几乎两打那样的背包
They sent out nearly two dozen of the backpacks.
并且是匿名广告
The poster used an I.P. Anonymizer,
让我们没办法追踪
Making it impossible to trace.
难道我们什么也做不了
So we just do nothing?
我把绑匪给我的手机
Well, I managed to slip the phone
放到那个包里面了
That the kidnappers gave me inside the backpack.
什么意思
I don't understand.
在那之前
Well, before I did that,
我给贝克特警探发了条信息
I sent a text message to detective Beckett.
手机是大单销售
The phone's under a bulk account,
查不到购买人的信息
So we can't trace its owner,
但能追踪到方位
But we can trace its I.D.
目前  查到它在下东区20条街区内
So far, we've pinged the phone to a 20-Block radius on the lower east side.
还需要几个小时把范围缩小
We'll need another few hours to narrow it down.
同时  我派了一组人过去
In the meantime, I've moved a team into the area.
他们会仔细排查  一旦得到更多消息
They'll work the streets, be ready to move
随时准备行动
When we have more information.
-谢谢  -嗯
- Thanks. - Mm-Hmm.
你还好吧
You okay?
我一直在想  要是我看到谁拿的就好了
I keep thinking, if only I saw who took that bag...
那不是你的工作
Well, that wasn't your job.
知道吗  我难以想象
You know I can't imagine
这样的事发生在阿丽克西斯身上会怎样
Anything like this ever happening to Alexis.
我们很快会救回她的
We'll get her back soon.
没有我们想的那么快
Not as soon as we hoped.
他们肯定发现了  把电池取出来了
They must've found it, taken the batteries out.
我们失去了手机的追踪信号
We just lost the signal from the phone.
怎么还不睡  担心期末考试
What are you doing up? Stressed about finals?
今天是美国不眠日
American lit's today.
我做噩梦  梦到海丝特·白兰
I was having nightmares about Hester Prynne.
但问题是不得"优"会让你难堪
The irony for you is not getting an "a" would cause you shame.
那你怎么还不睡
So why are you up?
我在找小白兔
Looking for a white rabbit.
路易斯·卡罗尔或者"黑客帝国"
Lewis Carroll or "The Matrix"?
还不确定
I'm not sure yet.
关于犯罪现场的拍照贝克特跟你说了什么
What did Beckett tell you about taking phone photos at the crime scene?
我不知道  没听
I don't know. I wasn't listening.
看到床上的那些动物娃娃了吗
See all those stuffed animals on the bed?
跟我以前的很像
It looks just like mine used to.
还记得我以前的那些娃娃吗
Remember when I had all those animals?
如果你是说Bonkey猴的话
If by remember when, " you mean Monkey-Bonkey,
被洗了那么多次  他现在看起来很惨
Who has been washed so many times he looks like roadkill now,
那么  是
Then, yes.
我搞不懂你在说些什么
I have no idea what you're talking about.
那么你不会介意下次我看到他的时候
Oh, then you won't mind next time I see him
-把他扔出去  -你敢
- If I throw him out. - Don't you dare!
-我不会  不会的  -绝对不要
- I won't, I won't. - Don't.
-不会的  -很好
- I won't. - Okay.
好
Okay.
你认为邦尼兔和这个案子有关
So you think the Bunny has something to do with the case?
等我到兔窝里看一下再告诉你
I'll let you know when I go down the rabbit hole.
卡塞尔
Castle?
继续睡吧
Go back to sleep.
你在干什么
What are you doing?
阿丽克西斯还小的时候
When Alexis was little,
她有一个很珍爱的猴子娃娃  整天抱着
She had a stuffed monkey that she could not live without.
有一次我们去度假  她忘了带上他了
One time we went on vacation, she forgot to pack him.
我又给她买了一个
I bought her another one,
但她知道不是原来那个
But she knew it was not monkey-Bonkey.
然后呢
So?
有几张照片都是她拿着这只邦尼兔
So there's two more pictures of her clutching this Bunny out there.
那么邦尼兔在哪儿呢
So where's the Bunny?
你认为绑匪很熟悉安吉拉的喜好
You think whoever took Angela knew her well enough
所以把邦尼兔也带上啦
To take the Bunny, too?
但我们已经查过坎德拉家的人员名单了
But we already checked the Candelas' list.
有几个年轻保姆
A couple of teenage babysitters,
一个清洁工  她们都被排除嫌疑了
A cleaning lady... They've all been cleared.
但不是所有保姆都是青少年
Only not all babysitters are teenagers.
有时候他们就是我们周围的人
Sometimes they're people close to us.
有时是家人
Sometimes they're family.
我们什么时候丢了手机上的信号的
When did we lose the signal on the phone?
在告诉坎德拉夫妇我们在追踪之后
Right after we told the Candelas we were tracking it.
特里萨的妹妹妮娜  你有她地址吗
Theresa's sister Nina-- You got an address?
妮娜·门多萨
Nina Mendoza,
你因绑架安吉拉·坎德拉而被捕了
You're under arrest for the kidnapping of Angela Candela.
竟然绑架自己的外甥女  把手放背后
Taking your own niece? Put your hands behind your back.
你有权保持沉默
You have the right to remain silent...
你好  安吉拉
Hello, Angela,
看到你真高兴
I am so happy to see you.
想见妈妈吗
You wanna go and see mommy?
来吧  宝贝  看看你  你好啊
Come on, baby. Look at you. Hello.
嗨  小美人
Hi, beautiful.
想要你的粉红小兔子吗  哦  看看这个兔子
You wanna grab your pink rabbit? Oh, look at the rabbit.
哦  天哪
Oh, my god.
安吉
Angie!
小心肝[西班牙语]
Mi coraz? N.Mwah!
哦...你看起来棒极了
Oh! Oh! Oh! God. You look perfect.
真是...太好了
Just... Perfect!
-她还好吧  -她很好
- Is she okay? - She's fine. Yeah.
亲爱的  你还坐那儿干什么
Honey... What are you doing?
她在这儿  她回来了
She's here! She's home!
你怎么啦  发生什么事了
What is it? What's wrong?
怎么回事
What's going on?
克劳福德  你能先带安吉拉离开吗
Crawford... Can you take Angela?
我们走  宝贝
Come here, sweetie.
-拿去  克劳福德  -谢谢  走喽
- Here you go, Crawford.  - Thank you. Here we go.
你做了什么
What did you do?
我一天工作14小时  一年又一年
I worked 14-Hour days, year after year,
拼命来供我们生活
Killing myself so that we can have a life.
而你做了些什么
And what did you do?
哦  你画画
Oh. You painted.
你只会画画
All you did was paint.
-不是那样的  -是吗
- That's not true. - Really?
你说你要找的那个工作怎么样了
What about that job you said that you were gonna get
那样我就能少工作一会儿了
So that I could cut my hours?
我在照顾安吉拉
I was taking care of Angela!
照顾  你把她扔在那儿
Taking care? You left her there...
每天把她放在电视机面前
In front of the TV every day!
你们知道我有多少次被她的尖叫声吵醒吗
Do you know how many times I woke up to her screams,
因为他在那个房间里  耳朵塞着耳机
Because he was in that room blasting the music in his ears?
但你也不能绑架你自己的孩子
It doesn't give you the right to kidnap your own child.
怎么是绑架  她是我女儿
How is it kidnapping? She's my daughter.
坎德拉太太  你让你妹妹
Mrs. Candela, you had your sister
从那个窗户爬进来带走她
Climb through that window and take her.
她得到了我的允许
I gave her permission.
那也不行
It doesn't matter.
你触犯了你丈夫的监护权
You violated your husband's custodial rights.
监护权
Custodial rights?
他根本都没有注意到她不见了
He didn't even notice that she was gone!
对两岁的孩子来说他到底算个什么父亲
What kind of a father does that to his 2-Year-Old child?
你为什么要这么做
Why would you do this?
为什么要搞成这样
Why would you put us through that?
为什么不直接和我离婚
I mean, for god's sake, why not just divorce me?
哦  然后你起诉我索要赡养费
Oh, so that you can sue me for alimony?
分得一半的财产
So that you can get half of everything?
获得安吉拉的监护权
So that you can get custody of Angela
因为我整天都要工作而你可以在那照顾她
Because I'm at work all day and you can "be there for her"?
没门
No.
我见识过了人在工作时的样子
I've seen what happens to the guys at work,
看到了道埃勒家族的下场
What happened to Doug Ellers.
我绝不会让那发生在我身上
No way was that gonna happen to me!
你在交赎金给自己
You were paying the ransom to yourself.
安吉拉一回来  我就申请离婚
Once Angela returned, I would file for the papers.
他就会一无所有了
There would be nothing left for him to take.
如果安吉拉是在阿尔弗雷德
And if Angela was kidnapped
照看她时被绑架了  那么
When Alfred was taking care of her, then--
律师说过
The lawyer said that
如果能证明他疏忽大意  我就能获得监护权
If I could prove him negligent, I would get custody.
我不需要搬出我买的房子
I wouldn't have to move out of the apartment that I paid for
因此他可以和我女儿住在这儿
So that he could live here with my daughter.
你们知道收养她有多难吗
Do you know how hard it was to adopt her,
代价有多大吗
How much it cost?
十年啊
Ten years!
你卖过几张画  阿尔弗雷德
How many paintings have you sold, Alfred? Huh?
几张
How many?
你为什么这么恨我
How could you hate me so much?
这都是你造成的
You made it easy.
你觉得她会怎样
So how do you think she'll do?
这取决于陪审团中有多少个母亲
Well, it depends on how many mothers are on the jury.
那么
So...
现在案子结了
Now that it's over...
我也要回去了  我原来..
Now that I'm back, I was...
打算我们可以旧梦重温
Thinking maybe we could give it another shot.
如果你又要离开呢
And when you leave again?
你跟我一起走
You come with me.
考虑一下吧
Think about it.
他很不错
Nice guy.
但我知道那不管用
I can see how it wouldn't work, though.
-是吗  -当然
- Really? - Sure.
英俊  方下巴  很端正
Handsome, square-Jawed, by-The-Book...
难道那不好吗
And that's a bad thing?
好啊  正符合你的标准
Yeah, he's like the male you.
阴阳结合  而不是阴阴结合
Yin needs yang, not another yin.
阴阳结合才协调
"Yin-Yang" is harmony.
"迎迎"还是个熊猫的名字
"Yin-Yin" is... A name for a panda.
还有什么至理名言吗  欧比旺
Any more wisdom, Obi-Wan?
没有了  今天就这些
Nope, that's it for today.
我们去喝一杯庆祝一下怎么样
What say we celebrate by going out for a drink?
不行  我有约会
I can't. I got a date.
约会  你在约会
A date? You date?
和谁
Who?
之所以有"私生活"这个词
That's why it's called a "private life,"
是因为这属于个人隐私
Because it's private.
不像你  我不会把我的生活暴露给别人
Unlike you, I don't live my life on "page six."
看来你是个很神秘的人  贝克特探长
Well, you're a mysterious woman, Detective Beckett.
可能我有尼基·希特身上不具备的东西
Maybe there's a little more Nikki Heat in me than you think.